Okay, we are now back and we are going to call to order the Miami City Council meeting
for today's date.
Second item on the agenda is Miss Kim Horn and the host of employees and we want to
recognize Kim.
Okay, we're going to recognize some employees that said me with the above and beyond award.
And we usually do this quarterly, but due to the holidays last quarter, we weren't able to
do that.
So we have quite a few tonight, but there are very well-deserving.
So I'm going to ask Adam Collins, he's an equipment operator at the Street Department
to please come up with Mike Edwards, who is his supervisor, the Street Manager, Mike nominated
Adam.
If you want to come on up, the little Mary, you're going to take your picture while reading the
information.
This is what Mike said.
On February 2nd, Adam was working in the Alia town in Founder Ladies, Wallet.
Adam brought me the Wallet and wanted to return it to the owner, we found the owner's ID and
we called the Insurance Company from the Verification.
About 10 minutes later, the owner called me an animal and they took her the Wallet.
There were six credit cards, a debit card and $743 in cash.
Needless to say, she was very thankful for Adam's honesty.
He deserves this.
Thank you, Adam.
Okay, our next recipient is Sam Dumbledore, she's a dispatcher in the police department.
She was actually nominated by two people, going to London, or emergency management director
in Dublin, Johnson, and there was another dispatcher that works with her.
This is what London had to say, although all MPD dispatchers did a phenomenal job during the
last flood of that sandal and was exceptional, she could call it the beginning of each of her
chefs for information in that date and would share this with the many calls she received.
Her assistant during the flood of that was invaluable, she did not have to answer questions
that she had permission to send her forward to calls to Glander, but Sandra took care of
that, she answered them the bus she could first and then transfer the call, personally,
she helped keep me signed in the first critical hours of this event.
And then the comments from our double that works with Sandra is basically, I have seen her handle
high stress calls and loving news, her temporal attack.
She's always willing to help everyone else and she thinks that Sandra is one of the dispatchers
that MPD has.
Congratulations.
Okay, one of our shaman-dinger, who is a common manager in Michael Richardson, who is a
IT director to come up, I actually nominated shaman-dinger Mikey and forward the work that they
do with the Paradise Veterans Hunt.
And both of us tonight is Jack Dellman-Poul, who is the local organizer of that hunt, and then
and Bill Clickenman-Dolphin, am I right Bill?
All right.
It's the president of the Middicate American PVA, so here's what I want to say about shaman.
He got another offer in the beginning of the hunt in 2008 when he was...
the publisher of the news record. The first time he helped with the publicity and the organization,
and then he was asked if he would ever see making sure everyone got fed. So now it sounds like he
is the chief cook for the events. He also helps with the flag raising ceremony, the banquet,
many, many other things. He also this year had the privilege of working with Deputy City
Clark Alisha Holden and City Manager Dean Coutel from Proclamations for each veteran participating in the
hunt. He said that it's truly an honor to be a small part of such an outstanding event. We say all
the time that this hunt is just our small way of thanking these great Americans for their service
and sacrifice to our country. We'll do it because it fills our hearts and joy every year to know
that even if it's for only a few days, we can have so much of an impact on these veterans lives.
Mikey, he started volunteering with the Ivana couple of years ago when he was asked by Jack Del Rempel.
He organized and staffed a fundraising booth at the event and he helped him create a
go-friendly page to raise money. He said it was truly an honor to be a small part of the event.
I see our community as a step up and help make this event very special every single year. To me,
it's all about the paralyzed veterans and making sure they'll have a memory that will last in a lifetime.
Nothing is more heartwarming than watching these veterans come back from hunting with a big smile on their face.
What I would like to say about both of these gentlemen, I nominated them. There are so many city employees
that do work with in our community and those of them are pretty humble and want to
share about this and I said in a way it's kind of time to tune around horn. We love our community
and we want them to highlight our city employees that are doing so much good work too. So,
Jack, do you want to sell a few words? We've got a lot of time.
I want to treat you, Jack.
I was going to say, we do not jack.
What's in the cut-blowner for me to be able to step up and say something and add to a little bit what
these two very talented and really quiet intelligent, and then add to this community.
I said they're talented and intelligent, but I didn't say that I'm not full of them.
Those events is more than just what it appears to be. It has become something that this community needs and wants.
And what's exciting to me about this thing is happening tonight. It reflects on multiple levels.
It reflects on any of the council in this entire city, recognizing that they are somebody special.
What they do is important. I can tell you right now, I need a one of them doing anything for a pat on the back
When they started this work, that was a further stung away from their mind, and in fact I
knew that they're both very uncomfortable to be standing up in letting the ad to this.
But what's important is that it identifies some of the things that makes our community so special and so different.
And I can tell you that because when our guests come to be at my animal coma, they tell me that and they tell me they don't understand why we do what we do.
And they're completely in all about the fact that this thing gets put together without any leadership, without any organization.
And the reason why that happens is because every person that works at it is led and organized by a dictates of his heart, which are coming from a much higher level than we could establish right here in my animal coma.
So that being said, I want to give that.
It's really strange because we don't give each other anything because we're all involved in involved in.
And making sure that our guests are happy.
But so this is the first.
I'm going to give them each something from the river by the sportsman.
It's a plaque that says in honor of Michael and Shannon, member of the river of the sportsman for disabled veteran recognizing national pride, selfless commitment to community, tireless dedication to our veterans, to guard our nation.
Thank you very much.
I think we'll be able to give you a work for you.
You came all the way from Oklahoma City.
There you go.
The bill is the president of the Mid-American chapter of the paralyzed veterans of American.
And this is the organization that we've worked with to help put the hunt on.
And there's the ones that responsible for getting our hunters.
And one thing is like Jack said, it's all about the victims.
And there you have it.
Probably 40.
Maybe a little bit.
Yes, sir.
The officers.
I have them.
They're set now.
Yeah.
Thank you.
Okay, I'm going to ask Sherry Spillers who is our CVB tourism sales coordinator in Amanda Davis to come out please.
Sherry was nominated by Amanda, who is the director of CVB and tourism.
This is what Amanda had to say. Sherry's work ethic is excellent and we're seeing a number of new groups expected to come in.
She has a renewed spirit and is working very hard as an asset to our tourism team.
She's willing to do anything required and she cares deeply about the success of the city of Miami.
An example of aboveing the jaundice when Sherry stepped up during the premier baseball tournament.
She cares about seeing the city move forward and she wants the best for Miami. Congratulations, Sherry.
Okay, Bapigil Clapp is our promotion control assistant manager.
She is nominated by Nancy Blair and if you guys will come up so we can get your picture.
This is what Nancy had to say about Bobby. She's very delicate and she's a hardworking and she's certainly loves her job.
I believe Bobby proves that every day about always thinking of ways of tracking all the important details that most of us take for granted.
Nancy mentioned what all of us in the city now, Bobby jail is an Excel genius.
And for some time she was for the most part the only person that was doing updates on the city webpage and Bobby's been very helpful with other employees.
But because of that and beyond and everything she does for the betterment of our city and our community congratulations, Bobby.
Okay, last but not least, I want to ask Derek Laurel and Colin Summer.
They're both joining the moment in Michael Robertson to come up. Michael is a fourth year apprentice on them.
They were nominated by the boss, Tyler Klein.
These guys are actually unsaved you to last because I'm very glad you're all here. Thank you.
They were actually representing not just themselves because they really didn't feel like they deserved this.
But on Christmas Day, they came in and worked for four hours. We had 1,500 customers that were out of power and got them back on.
I think that they said they wanted everyone to know as they're not only representing what they did, but all the people, all the city employees that work on holidays.
But my number one dispatchers, the fire department, solid waste, the water department.
So yes, you guys, this is above and beyond and we appreciate it.
But they want everyone to know that they appreciate all the other employees that do the same thing.
And I want to thank the council for letting us do this. I think it's really important.
So thank you very much.
Thank you.
Okay. Thank you, Kim.
I remember three, there's public input on schedule personal experiences.
Thank you.
to Council on any of the agenda items.
There are being none item four is considered gender staff is recommending items five to
attend for the consent agenda.
There are no questions.
We'll have a motion.
Most of it per month.
And the second.
Second.
We'll call.
Johnson.
All right.
West End.
Show.
Hi.
Thank you.
I have 11.
We're all out of this middle school future city presentation.
Has Michelle Townsley's day next to it.
Michelle.
I think they're out in the hall road bringing it in.
I remember this from last year.
It was a pretty awesome thing.
Yeah.
Very creative.
So I'll see what they have for us this year.
They made me do another door, man.
I don't know.
Traditionally.
Hey Travis.
We made you go with that door for them to be able to get through.
I don't try.
Today we have the.
World largest middle school here tonight.
They're teacher Michelle Townsley.
It's part of the future city competition.
The students created a city of the future.
They'll say what it's have you about tonight.
I still want to thank you for letting us come and show off our hard work.
These kids have worked really hard after school.
To build a city and come up with a design and a plan.
Or what they think would meet future demands.
And we had about 10 students.
We're really hard on this.
We're probably about three or four months.
And these are the dedicated ones that decided to show up tonight.
This is Michael.
And Sydney.
And Grayson.
And I'm going to let them talk to you about their city.
The city is Oceanis.
If Oceanis was a real city.
It would be underwater.
Food is made by 3D printers.
The trash system also is very complex.
Food for ocean and assistance is made from 3D printers.
Every house is a 3D printer much like a microwave.
You type what food you want and about 5 minutes of food appears.
Every bit of trash, energy, ocean, this is recycled.
Everything looks like rubber.
Styrofoam is completely banned.
Every button has a seat sheet that is committed to a money or another city.
Trust a stroke, shoulder by a large robot.
If there isn't an unidentified object, it stays on the monitor and it is dumped on a platform.
The platform works like a elevator and goes to it.
To a room with people that sort of sorted out.
Transporter.
You might remember that ocean assistance is underwater.
So how would people get around?
Transit tunnels under the sea floor connected to every building.
And the special lock systems that use iron, iron, iron, and hand scanner to get in.
Any questions from the audience?
Can one of you tell us a little bit about the city, what the different parts of it are?
These are the pieces we are on the power to make.
These are the geothermal plants.
The power goes to the city through the tube, electrical wires.
You guys want to turn it around and show them what you like about it.
Okay, so those are the robots.
Awesome.
And then I see you have a hotel and a recycling center.
The visitor center.
That's where a man works.
We're going to let him on.
That person has to say that.
art museum so you have some culture you know what's the black thing at the top
in the center there where the electrical lines are going as well as a loud
speaker okay and then there was the silver colored triangle in the front here
part okay those are the tubes okay having young kids it's almost like
sponge bulb meets who will I see you said it's no exception start from other
than it floats they obviously try very good answer well you guys are in the
outstanding job what's the next step from here is a regional competition
well actually there was a state competition in January that we weren't able to
go to so what our next step is we could we could go to the competition next year
so but that's one of the reasons I wanted to bring this to the city council meeting
and show you guys because they worked really hard on it and what grade were
your students these are all six six and seventh graders and we had a few eighth
graders working on it as well okay we're very proud of you three for showing them
you three in front of all of them and I want you guys to know that they actually took on
speaking parts from other students that didn't show up but
good job good job good job good job good good okay that's awesome
I don't remember 12 is new business any new business being I don't know 13 is
announcements near the GF something I did just just showing we have a lot of people
to thank for that the box and you're in the chamber Jack Brown from Brownlanders
so we'll be in the chair's pillars up here all the way down
she wasn't even asked to help and she volunteered to do that and she worked very hard
sorry so I don't think her and we even put her safety manager to work for a little bit
we got a good job but I had a lot of people think Ron Gilbert, Larry Roberts
just told a bunch of people yes that was a great article in the paper look like it was an outstanding
we had close to 300 and very good to know people you haven't seen it a long
yeah I would say I don't but yeah I've been along well I was at 38th Anniversary
is that right yeah it was 30 years since plant closed
one of the neatest things about that is we brought the old BF good rich bricks that we had
a lot of people took a misovenirs and we had a lot of people picking up and now I understand
the top of the center is going to be taking the rest of the bricks and maybe incorporate it
into some walkways and things like that in Miami so the building will live on
all right I don't think city manager communications do you? well I did want to congratulate Neil
on the reunion that was really a lot of fun and that's going to be leading into our 120th
Anniversary that's coming up on Thursday just a reminder to everybody that on Thursday
March 3rd from noon to 3 here at the Civic Center will have a celebration and at 2 o'clock
and that's why I've asked you to be here at 2 o'clock we'll have the celebration ceremony
with the birthday cake as well I believe Lieutenant Governor's going to be here we're inviting
a number of other dignitaries represented if those are our tribes past city council members
so it should be a lot of fun for 30 then we start the parade downtown and I understand a lot of people
are signing up for that so first time we've done one of these in a long time and then 730 that
not just are still available but they're going very fast celebration concert at the
Coleman Theatre levy town featuring Jacques Aruit and Jack is from Miami and he plays in the
Kansas City area quite a bit. Friday March 4th it's going to be celebrate Miami so it's going to be
an education day with our students and schools then there's going to be an evening concert at Buffalo
Run with our own Keith Anderson and then Saturday March 5th starting at 11 o'clock to 3 there's
going to be an all-school reunion at the Miami Activity Center at the high school and light snacks are
going to be there so if you're a wardog or maybe to wardog or just want to see all the wardogs come on out
so that's what's taking place now while I'm at line Amanda has done a great job with commitment to shirts
that we're putting out and also updated the 100th anniversary calendar to 125th anniversary
calendar so she's done a terrific job on that really when you consider the planning for their
event only really started just before the first of the year and it's amazing how far we've come along on that
so I just want to thank him for that but I don't think I just
to bring out this is just a little housekeeping item. You know that we've been doing some work on
north-end street with a housing project that we had up there. We had a little bit of drainage problems.
Travis wanted to tell everybody that Anderson Engineering did the revised grading plan last
of November. We had ITC construction take care of it. We had seven properties were altered.
One on the west side that had flooding issues and the six on the east side where they had standing water.
Our grading was just finished last Friday on the 26th. The sod was laid Monday the 29th and the work has
been to close out the grants. So this is something M2DA has been working on pretty much since I've
been here and I'd like to report to we've got that closed down. So that's my important part of your honor.
I have one more thing. I've got to mention I want to thank the random Jim Miller from the
news record for getting the story out. That really helped appreciate that. Really worth it. Yeah.
Yeah. Thank you, William. Okay. I have a 15 executive session,
pursuing the 25 OS 307 B1 and B4 and 307 E. Do we have a motion to go into the executive session
for the reason it's listed on the item 15 of the agenda? Make a motion, you know.
The second. Second. What we call please?
For a start.
All right.
Weston.
Johnson.
All right.
Shows.
Okay.
We can clear the room. We'll try to do this pretty quickly.
Back out of the executive session in 608 p.m. Next time on the agenda is the German.
We have a motion to adjourn. Most of them adjourn.
And a second. Second.
Johnson. For a start.
Five. Weston. All right. Shows.
All right. We're going in there. Thank you. And now y'all.